Streetfare Journal poetry posters, 1984-1997 PS615 .S89
Lilly Library
Streetfare Journal poetry posters
1984-1997
Lilly Library
Niedecker, Lorine
Blackburn, Paul
Gunn, Thom
Olson, Charles, 1910-1970
Oppen, George.
Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1917-2000
Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005
Levertov, Denise, 1923-.
Bukowski, Charles
Corman, Cid
Paz, Octavio, 1914-1998
Amichai, Yehuda, 1924-2000
Enslin, Theodore, 1925-
Laughlin, James, 1914-1997
Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-2019
Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979.
Di Prima, Diane
Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930
Antonio Machado
Neruda, Pablo, 1904-1973.
Tarn, Nathaniel, 1928-
Celan, Paul, 1920-1970
Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980
Hughes, Langston, 1902-1967
Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967
Stevens, Wallace, 1879-1955.
Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963
PS615 .S89
1 linear foot
The Streetfare Journal poetry posters consist of a collection of all 102 full color interior bus posters featuring poetry and visual art for display on urban bus systems throughout the U.S.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquisition information unknown
Historical Note
The Streetfare Journal poetry series was sponsored by TDI (Transportation Displays Incorporated) and grants from the Lannan Foundation (Los Angeles), the National Endowment for the Arts (Washington, D.C.), the Lila Wallace-Reader's Digest Fund (New York), (internationally) the Australia Council for the Arts, and other agencies.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 102 full color interior bus posters featuring poetry and visual art for display on urban bus systems throughout the U.S. The broadsides feature 103 poets and translators, and 41 visual artists. Highlights include: Charles Bukowski, Robert Creeley, Diane di Palma, James Laughlin, Denise Levertov, Michael McClure, Pablo Neruda, William Carlos Williams, Ansel Adams, Michael Kenna, Dorothea Lange, Black Sparrow Press, City Lights Books, The Ecco Press, New Directions, Persea Books, and many other people and publishers. Bulk of the collection is American poets, however poets from other countries are represented.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Related Materials
See Corman mss., Corman mss. III, and Célan, Paul mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Literature--translating; Bus travel; Nicaraguan poetry; Australia -- Poetry; Vietnamese poetry; American poetry--20th century.
- Early Series, 1984-1986; 11" X 28" broadsides, 2 color or 3-color printing, on card stock except where noted
  - George Evans, "The Loss"
    Scope and Contents
    First Series [unnumbered/no date, on styrene, typography]
  - Thom Gunn, "Well Dennis O'Grady"
  - August Kleinzahler, "Lightning Bugs"
  - Charles Olson, "These Days"
    Vol. II, No. 1 [no date, typography]
  - George Oppen, "The Forms of Love"
    Vol. II, No. 2 [no date, typography]
  - Bobbie Louise Hawkins, "Curtis stuck his foot..."
    Vol. II, No. 2 [no date, prose, illustrated]
  - Lorine Niedecker, "Laundromat"
    Vol. II, No. 3 [no date, illustrated]
  - Lorine Niedecker, "Remember my little granite pail..."
  - Paul Blackburn, "Matchbook Poem"
    Vol. II, No. 4 [no date, illustrated]
  - Charles Reznikoff, "I thought for a moment..."
    Vol. II, No. 5 [no date, illustrated]
  - Robert Hayden, "Crispus Attucks"
    Vol. III, No. 1 [no date, illustrated]
  - Robert Hayden, "Sojourner Truth"
- 6 Poster Poetry Series, 1987-1997; 11" X 28" broadsides, 4 color printing, on card stock
  - Unnumbered, no date [Vol. IV, No. 1], Spring 1987
    - Mary Barnard, "Soft Chains"
      With misc. graphics
    - Gwendolyn Brooks, "We Real Cool"
    - Robert Creeley, "Wisdom"
    - Denise Levertov, "Concurrence"
    - Carl Rakosi, "The Experiment with a Rat"
    - Gary Soto, "Field Poem"
  - Vol. IV, No. 2 [Native American Series], Fall 1987
    - Ray A. Young Bear, "The Personification of a Name"
    - Steve Crow, "Revival"
    - Nora Dauenhauer, "Voices"
    - Joy Harjo, "Eagle Poem"
    - N. Scott Momaday, "The Story of a Well made Shield"
    - Mary TallMountain, "Matmiya"
  - Vol. V, No. 1 [First series featuring visual art with poetry], Spring 1988
    - Charles Bukowski, "oh yes"
      With a drawing by Roy de Forest
    - Lucille Clifton, "why some people be mad at me sometimes"
      With a painting by Miriam Schapiro
    - Cid Corman, "When was this to be?"
    - Bob Kaufman, "Mingus"
      With a painting by Joe Sam
    - Genny Lim, "Nostalgia"
      With a painting by Kenneth Noland
    - Octavio Paz, "La Exclamación"/"Exclamation"
      With a painting by George McNeil
  - Vol. V, No. 2, Fall 1988
    - Yehuda Amichai, "Forgetting Someone"
    - Theodore Enslin, "No one returns..."
      With a painting by Clyfford Still
    - Paulette Jiles, "Paper Matches"
      With a painting by Joan Mitchell
    - Roberto Juarroz, "Y no sé hacer un hombre... ."/"I don't know how to make a man... ."
      With a painting by O.O. Johns
    - James Laughlin, "A Failure of Communication in the Animal Kingdom"
      With a painting by Robert Motherwell
    - Lorine Niedecker, "Sewing a Dress"
      With a painting by Morris Louis
  - Vol. VI, No. 1, Spring 1989
    - Jimmy Santiago Baca, "I have been lost from you Mother Earth.. ."
      With a painting by Hon Sum Kwok
    - Rosario Castellanos, "Consejo de Celestina"/"Celestina's Advice"
      With a painting by Jake Berthot
    - Victor Hernandez Cruz, "Side 5"
      With a painting by Sachio Yamashita
    - George Evans, "Eye Blade"
      With a painting by Hon Sum Kwo
    - Linda Hogan, "The Hands"
      With a painting by Li Hua
    - Nanao Sakaki, "One Two Three Four"
      With a painting by Larry Poons
  - Vol. VI, No. 2, Fall 1989
    - Richard Caddel, "There are ribbons of stream.. ."
      With a black & white photograph by Ansel Adams
    - Henry Dumas, "Fir"
      With a black & white photograph by David Lubbers
    - Miyazawa Kenji, "The Snow on Saddle Mountain"
    - W.S. Merwin, "The Inevitable Lightness"
    - Gary Snyder, "The Great Mother"
      With a black & white photograph by Michelle Vignes
    - Tomas Tranströmer, "Sketch in October"
  - Vol. VII, No. 1, Summer 1990
    - Elizabeth Bishop, "Rain Towards Morning"
      With a painting by Frank Stella
    - Jayne Cortez, "The Red Pepper Poet"
      With a painting by James Cobb
    - Jack Marshall, "Dawn Notes"
      With a painting by James Rosenquist
    - Diane Di Prima, "Numbers Racket"
      With a painting by Robert Goodnough
    - Michael Smith, "Sunday"
      With a painting by Maria Baca
    - Gary Soto, "A Red Palm"
  - Vol. VII, No. 2, Spring 1991
    - William Bronk, "Spring Storm"
      With a black & white photograph by Michael Kenna
    - Beatrice Hawley, "Recovery"
    - D.H. Lawrence, "Conscience"
    - Denise Levertov, "Envy"
    - Antonio Machado, "In between living and dreaming.. ."/"Entre el vivir y el soñar.. ."
    - Charles Olson, "These Days"
  - Vol. VII, No. 3, Winter 1991-1992
    - Thomas McGrath, "Parable"
      With a painting by Richard Diebenkorn
    - Ariwara No Narihira, "I have always known..."
      With a lithograph by Toko Shinoda
    - Pablo Neruda, "I have learned about life"/"He aprendido la vida.. ."
    - Janet Rodney, "Remember.. ."
    - Nathaniel Tarn, "The Silence"
      With a painting by Gerhard Richter
    - Quincy Troupe, "Passing On the Legacy"
  - Vol. VII, No. 4, Fall/Winter 1992-1993
    - Paul Celan, "Discus"
      With a black & white photograph by Sebastião Salgado
    - Robert Desnos, "Earth"
    - Sigitas Geda, "The collective request of the dead country children from Patern Village"
    - Ho Xuan Huong, "Spring-Watching Pavilion"
    - George Oppen, "A Political Poem"
    - Aleksandar Ristovic, "Untitled"
  - Vol. VII, No. 5, Fall/Winter 1993
    - Lucille Clifton, "atlas"
      With a black & white photograph by Mary Ellen Mark
    - Wanda Coleman, "The Heebeegeebees"
    - Michael McClure, "Not Youth"
    - Yannis Ritsos, "A man smiles by himself.. ."
    - Muriel Rukeyser, "Time comes into it... ."
    - Xavier Villaurrutia, "Nocturno Preso"/"Nocturne: Imprisoned"
  - Vol. VIII, No. 1, 1994
    - Langston Hughes, "Advice"
      With a black & white photograph by Dorothea Lange
    - Lorine Niedecker, "Foreclosure"
    - Charles Reznikoff, "I would be the rock.. ."
    - Carl Sandburg, "Dust"
    - Wallace Stevens, "I measure myself.. ."
    - William Carlos Williams, "El Hombre"
  - Vol. VIII, No. 2 [Australian Series], 1995
    - David Campbell, "Bobingah"
      With a painting by Pinta Pinta Tjapanangka
    - Robert Churnside (Ngarluma), "Goanna Hibernating"
      With a painting by Jeannie Nungarrayi Egan
    - Laurie Duggan, "The Mysteries"
      With a painting by Clarise Nampijinpa Poulson
    - John Kinsella, "The Orchardist"
      With a painting by Alec Mingelmanganu
    - Oodgeroo of the tribe Noonuccal (formerly known as Kath Walker), "Gifts"
      With a painting by Curly Bardkadubbu
    - John Tranter, "A Fit"
      With a painting by Mick Kubarkku
  - Vol. IX, No. 1 [Vietnam Series], 1996
    - Kevin Bowen, "River Music"
      With a color photograph by Mitch Epstein
    - George Evans, "Walking with the Enemy"
    - Yusef Komunyakaa, "Facing It"
    - Bruce Weigl, "Elegy for Peter"
    - Vietnamese Folk Poem (Ca Dao), "Love Lament" [bilingual Vietnamese/English]
    - Vietnamese Folk Poem (Ca Dao), "The Carp" [bilingual Vietnamese/English]
  - Vol. IX, No. 2 [Nicaragua Series (bilingual Spanish/English)], 1997
    - Claribel Alegría, "Challenge"/"Desafío"
      With a black & white photograph by Claudia Gordillo
    - Ernesto Cardenal, "If you are in New York"/"Si tú estás en Nueva York.. ."
    - Ana Ilce Gómez, "Hourglass"/"Reloj de arena"
    - Joaquín Pasos, from "The War Song of Things"/de "Canto de guerra de las cosas"
    - Ernesto Mejía Sánchez, "The Cross"/"La cruz"
    - Daisy Zamora, "To Be a Woman"/"Ser mujer"